ROSS LILLIS

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Parkville, Melbourne VIC 3052 +61 418 993 349 ross.lillis@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/ross-lillis | https://github.com/roscolil

ABOUT ME

Enthusiastic and committed Web Developer with 2+ years experience. I love coding because there is nothing more satisfying than solving problems and seeing your ideas come to life. I especially get a kick out of finding and learning new libraries and frameworks, and getting the front and back ends working together.

My goal is to become a valued contributor for startups and/or established businesses requiring a highly motivated, passionate technologist with a willingness to learn, a focus on continuous improvement both personally and professionally, and an easy going attitude.

SKILLS

HTML5/CSS3

Javascript

Node.is

React.js

Typescript

Gatsby.js

Jest/Enzyme

SQL

Ruby on Rails

Git & GitHub

Sass

AWS EB/S3

Netlify

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive,

Nov '17-Mar '18 (see below)

PM Partners

Prince2 Practitioner, 2007

Interim Technology

Diploma IT (Business

Programming), 1999-2000

- CompTIA Linux+
- ITIL Service Management Essentials

EXPERIENCE

Nura

Web Developer, 2019 - 2021

- Delivering changes and continuous improvements to Nura's customer-facing website (www.nuraphone.com) and eCommerce platform
- Maintaining and building upon existing infrastructure and delivering feature changes across the full tech stack including but not limited to Webflow CMS, SQL, Ruby on Rails, Shopify, AWS Elastic Beanstalk and S3.
- Commenced re-platforming of nuraphone.com to gatsby.js/react/netlify utilising Agile development practises
- Use website experimentation/testing to continually optimise customer journeys from first impressions through to purchase
- Collaboration with UX/UI team members to deliver cutting edge visual experiences
- Building front-end components and scripting to support multiple promotional and product campaigns

Coredna

Web Developer, 2018-2019

- Working with Front End and Back End teams to develop and maintain client sites built upon Coredna's Digital Experience Platform
- Utilising Javascript/jQuery, HTML, CSS/Sass and Smarty PHP templating language to integrate new features and front-end logic into customer sites
- Translating customer requests into technical specifications in agreed timeframes
- Cross device/browser support and testing
- Bitbucket, Jira and Confluence for documentation

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive Alumni, 2017-2018

- Designed and built secure full-stack web applications using both Javascript and Ruby on Rails
- Experience with associated frameworks and libraries
- Deployed applications to the web using cloud-based hosting and storage
- Working knowledge of web API's/RESTful web services

Projects:

- Find me Fodder: Location based restaurant finder (*React.js*, *JSX*, *Javascript*. *zomato api*) https://roscolil.github.io/find me fodder/
- King Pong: Ping pong tournament generator (*Ruby on Rails, Javascript/jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Heroku*) https://kingpongapp.herokuapp.com/
- Carrel: Book search and library catalogue (Ruby, google books api, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Heroku) https://carrelcatalogue.herokuapp.com/
- Tic Tac Toe: Modern noughts & crosses game (HTML, CSS, Javascript) https://roscolil.github.io/wdi project1 thegame/

Aluline Commercial Pty Ltd

Project Manager, 2010 - 2017

- Supported the business through considerable expansion from 10 to over 60 employees within a 5 year period and double digit year on year revenue growth
- Managed the end to end process of quoting, production and installation of commercial balustrade systems for the building industry
- Assumed a consultative and supervisory role between the client, our business and its workforce
- Through ongoing review, identified risks to timelines and program schedules and documented changes and variations

Prodrive Asia Pacific Pty Ltd

Technology Services Manager, 2006 - 2009

- Delivered business value through effective and relevant use of technology and management of IT resources to 5 business entities across Asia in a shared services support structure
- Managed a project portfolio containing works to support organisational change efforts including implementations of Share Point Portal, Microsoft AX, regional datacenter infrastructure and manufacturing facility for Toyota TRD.

Computer Associates (CA)

Systems Administrator, IT Manager - Pacific, 2000 - 2006

- Reporting to the CIO Asia Pacific Japan, managed a team of 10 system administrators (Level 2/3) supporting 12 sites and 2 call centres across Australia and New Zealand
- Direct involvement in day to day operations of computing and related equipment and telecommunications/data networks
- Budgetary and financial accountability to the business (Approx \$US3m annual capital/operating budget)
- Supported approx. 350 users over 3 sites in a Windows LAN/WAN networking environment.
- Managed various IT projects in southern region including relocation and expansion of Vet AV development lab
- Evaluate and implement department's backup and disaster recovery plan, assist in anti-virus rollout and documenting network infrastructure to ensure business continuity.